Welcome in Commanders family to a
special next man up a free agency
Fridays version of next man up here in
the Big Bear AI Command Center studio.
I'm here with a familiar face. Y'all all
know him. Treylon Burks in the building.
First things first brother,
congratulations man. Appreciate you. And
so how dope is this moment here? You got
your family here getting to be able to
share that with them. Your daughter is
1-year old. This got to be her first
time being able to do this with you,
right?
>> Um
Man, I'll just give it to God. It's all
God. We wouldn't be able to do it
without him.
Um
but it's
I don't know. Words can't explain man.
Um just
going through it, you know, I've been
through stuff like that. Um
I just use it as a stepping stone for me
to
keep going. Um there's a bigger purpose
and I couldn't be more blessed for sure.
Man, in everything you've been through
up until this point, you know, I'm sure
there was moments where this didn't even
feel promised where another contract was
a question mark for you because you
didn't know what was going to happen
man.
Are you able to breathe a little bit
today after putting putting that pen to
paper and just being able to say man
I've made [snorts] it this far. Like
yeah, there's a lot I want to do but
I've made it this far. I would say just
sort of type of person I am. No. Mhm. I
I I know there's more for me
more in me
not on the money ass side of it but just
I don't I don't give myself a chance to
sit back and think oh I've signed a
paper. I can relax. No, I don't feel
like that just because
you never know man. It could be taken
away just like that and so I don't take
anything for granted and you know, I'm
extremely blessed you know, to do that
but I'm just ready to get to work.
How ready to get to work? So
after the season you had last you played
eight games with us.
After making a catch like that, I got to
imagine
people were knocking at your door saying
hey man, we want to bring Burks over
here bring some of that magic over here.
What made you say you know what nah,
I'mma kick it with Washington instead.
>> Um
It's just family. Um when I first got
here on the when I was doing the
workouts, I could just tell by the
energy seeing literally
from the special teams
to the defensive coordinator to the
offensive coordinator and all their
staff AP and DQ were all in there.
Um
when I was doing my workout last year
and
and at some other places it wasn't like
that. And it just made me feel a little
different and then to get out there and
practice with the guys to get to know
everybody in the building, it just was
I don't know. It just felt like home.
And then coming in and seeing everybody
with the same
attitude and
emotions never change. Like they were
the same people every day. It
plays a big role in this league and I
just feel like that's what I wanted to
be a part of. Have you got to speak with
Dan Quinn a little bit since re-signing
and coming back?
>> Yes. Yeah, what are those conversations
like? Just
exciting man.
Ready to get to work. Um
play some ball for sure. And you
mentioned all those coaches watching
you. Now I don't know if coordinators
were involved or anything like that but
now we got a guy in David Blough For
sure. who's going to be your offensive
coordinator. You said he's your dog.
Everybody says everybody loves the guy.
How happy were you to know that he was
going to be your offensive coordinator?
Did that play a role in you wanting to
come back?
>> Uh yes.
You know, just
getting to know him last year
when he would be in there
and we would be doing walk-throughs at
6:00 a.m. He would he would be with
Jayden and I would be with um
my coach and
you know, Bobby would just always just
harp on the little details and then
eventually uh coach Blough he started
coming over there talking to us when we
were doing the you know, walk-through
and everything and you know, it just
I don't know. We just established a
great relationship with each other and
you know, he put in a couple you know,
passing plays for me to throw the ball.
So
>> Okay.
last year. So I mean it's just you can
just tell a bond when you meet somebody.
You know what I mean? You can just tell
that they're a great person and you
know, I just wanted to you know, get
back and you be around that. So That's
why it's great talking to y'all because
with a first time offensive coordinator
everybody's wondering what it's going to
look like, what the scheme's going to
look like, what to expect. From what
you've seen and been able to work with
him in real time, what do you expect
this offense to look like? How do you
expect it to develop and change?
>> I think it's going to be
really good. Um
So how about that? You good.
>> And I think you know, God's going to
take care of the rest of that. Um and
you know, make sure that you know, it is
what he wants it to be.
Um
but
I don't want to talk about it too much
and jinx it. You know what I mean? But
I'm excited for it for sure. You
definitely seem like a cat that's
control what I can control, focus on
what I can focus on. And I feel like
this off season was probably a little
different for you than what you've dealt
with because you have had injuries. A
lot of it has been rehab, focus on
getting better. This year wasn't that.
This year you got to really lock in and
focus on your craft. What were some of
those things you focused on in the off
season? Honestly just
getting back to myself. I feel like just
being Treylon.
Being who I am, hunting and fishing and
football.
Um
and there's no specific order with that.
Yes [laughter] sir.
But yeah man, just grinding and having
fun.
Y'all going to have to edit that.
>> Listen, when you got that money coming
in your phone [laughter] going to be
blowing up. It's all good brother.
>> Actually that was that was my daily
Bible. Oh amen. Okay. Shout out to God.
Sometimes God going to call you got to
answer.
>> Exactly.
>> [laughter]
>> Um but no man, just um
you know, finding myself being able to
go out and work out and not have to
worry about oh I got to go do rehab
right after this. I can go work out and
get a extra workout in after that and my
body feels great. And that's you know,
that's just part of who God you know
wanted me to be in that journey that he
put me down and you know, I'm just
extremely blessed brother. Extremely
blessed. God is good. Yes sir. Yes sir.
And then you mentioned Bobby Ingram so I
want to talk about him because you know,
we're here there on the sideline with
you guys on the road where I practice a
lot of times and Bobby is always with
you. It seems like Bobby's always taking
that extra step to kind of help you
grow. Just a great guy. You guys are
very similar in you guys's personality.
How has Bobby been able to help you kind
of get back to Treylon and get back to
who you feel like you are?
>> Man, that's
if honestly if it wouldn't
for him
I honestly wouldn't be like
like I don't know how to put it. Like he
brought that fun back for me.
Like going out there being who I am,
grinding and just letting it be. Control
what you control and God will take care
of the rest. You know, he brought that
back for me when I got here and I was
signed to practice squad. Like just
going out there and practicing against
the other guys, it was fun doing that
and to know that
my coach is going to sit down with me
and watch this film or he's going to
correct this about me and bro, you don't
get that all the time
because I just feel like sometimes
as players we feel like oh if I've
caught 500 something balls off the jugg
I don't need to go catch no more.
He's the opposite. You know, he he's I
mean even though you did that you can
still get 10 more. You know what I mean?
It won't hurt. What is it going to hurt?
Just just him being who he is and then
the way that he talks about Christ is a
big thing for me cuz I'm a big follower
and he is too and he preaches that day
in and day out. You know, and that's a
big thing for me and I also think that
that's why I'm here.
You know, so
Amen.
>> Happy to be back with him also. That's
fly man. That's dope to hear because
that's kind of how Bobby carries it and
you come in and you're really that one
of those first weapons that we bring in
and say okay, this is going to be part
of our new look offense with our new
offensive coordinator. Jayden Daniels
year three. You know better than anybody
how big year threes are for young
players man. How do you think you being
here and being back can help Jayden in
his development?
>> Um
out the roof. Just giving him the
confidence to
know Treylon's down there
somewhere throw it or Terry's down there
somewhere throw it or whoever it is. Um
but just giving him that confidence to
you know, that he's got guys out there
that got his back day in and day out.
And then just bringing that fun and
drive out of you know, him, me,
everybody in the room. You know what I
mean? And
I just think it's going to be a good
year of just for the whole organization
itself. And we're excited man. So
excited to have you back in that
burgundy and gold. In closing you said
getting back to Treylon Burks. In your
words, who is Treylon Burks and who are
you trying to get back to?
Um
I I I'll just say
I was a I was a little boy my great
grandma used to say this the little boy
from Johnson Street.
That's who I am. And that's having fun
being there for everybody, making plays,
scoring touchdowns
getting back up when you get knocked
down
and just being a Burks. Man, that's who
my great grandfather instilled in me and
that's what I'mma carry on. So Well, I'm
sure your great grandfather and all your
family are very proud of you my brother.
Getting back to Treylon Burks and now
Burks got a little more extra money in
his [laughter] pocket today. You I know
y'all peep the boots. My boy came in
styling man. Treylon, we appreciate you
so much man. Hope you enjoyed this time
celebrating with your family and and
your beautiful daughter man. We
appreciate it sir. Commanders family on
next man up as part of free agency
Fridays. We brought him back to run it
back. 1 3 Treylon Burks man. Appreciate
you dog. Appreciate y'all.